Do you realize that four weeks from today we're getting married?
你知道再四個星期 我們就要結婚了嗎？
Four weeks, baby!
四個星期，寶貝，四個星期！
Four weeks!
Do you realize that you get louder each week?
你知道每星期你都更大聲嗎？
There's still so much to do.
還有這麼多事要做！ 你寫好你的婚誓了嗎？
Have you written your vows yet?
I figured I'd just buy those.
我想我會去買 「派得，我要買婚誓」
Pat, I'd like to buy a vow.
Sweetie, you know I have no sense of humor when it comes to the wedding.
你知道講到婚禮的事 我是沒有幽默感的
All right, so have you written yours yet?
還有這麼多事要做！ 你寫好你的婚誓了嗎？
No, but I know exactly what I'm going to say.
你會不會剛好知道 我要講什麼？
Do you happen to know exactly what I'm going to say?
All right, let's just do it right now, okay?
希望他們的婚姻成功
Won't be hard.
現在來做，不會那麼難的
Just say what's in your heart.
說你心裡想的
Look at her go.
你看看這小東西
She must love me more than I love her.
看她寫得多快，她一定愛我 比我愛她多！
What's wrong with me?
我有什麼問題？ 不要打開那扇門
Oh, don't open that door.
So no one told you life was going to be this way?
你現在相信她喜歡上我了吧？
Your job's a joke, you're broke, your love life's the old way.
-你說你愛我！我不能相信 -不，我沒有
It's like you're always stuck in second gear.
你的東西都會在這裡
But when it hasn't been your day, week, or month, you've got to start over.
真不能相信再四個星期 他們就要結婚了！
Even though you're here, but I'll be there for you
現在有足夠的人知道了 就可以告訴他們我們知道
I'll be there for you too
-因為我愛摩妮卡 -你什麼？
Monica, there are no words
「摩妮卡，沒有字…」
There are no words!
This should not be this hard
沒有字！不應該這麼難的！
Oh, hey, you've done this before, Ross
你做過這事 你的婚誓裡說什麼？
Well, what did you say when you made up your vows?
Well, with Carol, I promised never to love another woman until the day I die
對卡蘿，我答應直到我死 不再愛另一個女人
She made no such promise
她沒有這樣答應我
I'm so pathetic
-所以… -對！
Monica knows what she wants to say
你會不會剛好知道 我要講什麼？
You should have seen her writing and writing and writing
你們要結婚了，非常的好
Monica, what? What is the emergency?
什麼緊急大事？
You have to help me
-我一定要告訴人 -不，不要！
I'm supposed to be writing my vows and all I have is this
幫我忙，我需要寫我的婚誓 可是我只有這些
Well, I like the pretty little drawing of you in the wedding dress
我喜歡你穿婚紗的圖劃
Yeah, except your breasts look kind of small
除了你的胸部看來有點小
Those are my eyes
那些是我的眼睛！
Those are my breasts
-那是我的胸部 -是，好吧
Oh, yeah, okay
是呦！
Why don't you just start with something simple?
何不從簡單的開始，像是：
Like, um, Monica, from the moment I met you, I knew I loved you
「摩妮卡，第一次見到你 我就知道我愛你」
Yeah, I'm not sure I can do that
我不確定我能這麼說
Everyone, this is Chandler
各位，這是錢德
Hi, I'm Ross' little sister
我是羅斯的小妹
Okay
是
Okay, okay, okay
好，好，我來
Um, maybe you could start with Chandler, even though we were friends
錢德，即使在我們還是朋友時…
there was a part of me that always knew I wanted more
一部份的我一直知道我要更多
Alright, there's a nuclear holocaust
好吧，有一場核子浩劫 我是地球上最後一個男人
I'm the last man on earth
Would you go out with me?
你會和我約會嗎？
Oh, are we allowed to lie in the vows?
婚誓裡可以說謊嗎？
Or maybe you don't talk about your feelings back then
也許那時你不談你的感情
Maybe you just say something about, you know, all the things that he's taught you, like
說些他教會你的事，像是…
Or all the things you taught him
或是你教會他的事
Everybody knows the basic erogenous zones
大家都知道基本的性感帶 有1，2，3…
You got one, two, three, four
-你會有一個的 -是啊，什麼時候？
Five, six, and seven
4，5… 6和7
There are seven?
有7個？
That's one?
菲比，沒有的事
Kind of an important one
-那算是一個嗎？ -蠻重要的
Oh, you know what? I was looking at it upside down
我是倒著看的
Ah, well, you know, sometimes that helps
有時候這樣也有幫助的
Okay, now start out with a little one
好，現在，由1開始…
A one, a two
一個4，一個32…
A one, two, three
一個2，一個123…
A three
一個3，一個5…
A five
A four
2，一個246
A three, two
一個4，一個32…
Two
不
A two, four, six
2，一個246
Two, four, six
Four
2，一個246
Two
不
Four, seven
Five, seven
Six, seven
Seven
Seven, seven, seven
Seven, seven, seven, seven
Oh, I got it
什麼？我不懂
I was saying something like, Monica
我知道了！這樣如何：
Monica
摩妮卡？
When I look back over our time together
「摩妮卡，回顧我們在一起的時間…」
Yeah?
是呦！
I can't do everything
我做得到
Look back over your time together
回顧你們在一起的時間
Oh, look, Joanne's
看，雙胞胎！
No fair
不，不
I don't even have one
不公平！我連一個都沒有 為什麼他們有兩個？
How come they get two?
You'll get one
-你會有一個的 -是啊，什麼時候？
Oh, yeah? When?
是呦！
All right, I'll tell you what
好！
When we're 40, if neither of us are married
這樣吧 當我們40的時候，如果我們 都沒結婚，
What do you say you and I get together and have one?
-我們倆來生一個如何？ -我為什麼會40歲還沒結婚？
Why wouldn't I be married when I'm 40?
假設這樣 我為什麼會40歲還沒結婚？
Oh, no, no, no
不，不
I just meant hypothetically
不，不，我是說假設這樣
Okay, hypothetically
Why won't I be married when I'm 40?
假設這樣 我為什麼會40歲還沒結婚？
No, no, no
不，不
No, no, what is it?
什麼？我不懂
Seriously, is there something fundamentally unmarriable about me?
怎麼著？真的，我是有什麼 基本上不能結婚的地方嗎？
Uh, uh
是呦！
Well?
怎麼樣？
Dear God, this parachute is a knapsack
我的老天 這個降落傘是一個背包！
I'm getting married today
今天我要結婚了！
Oh, woo-hoo
是呦！
You think he knew I was here?
他知道我在這兒嗎？
Nice try
算你盡力
Wait, wait, wait, wait
等一下，等一下，等一下
Look, Monica
摩妮卡…
This is not gonna work
-沒有用的 -我保證這有用
But this will work
可是這是大事！
You are so great, I love you
你真棒！我愛你
What?
什麼？
Nothing, I said, I said you're so great
沒事！我說，你真棒 然後就沒說話了
And then I just, I just stopped talking
You said you love me, I can't believe this
-你說你愛我！我不能相信 -不，我沒有
No, I didn't
-有，你有 -沒有，我沒有！
Yes, you did
No, I didn't
-有，你有 -沒有，我沒有！
You love me
-你愛我！ -不，我不！
No, I don't
Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it
停！停！
You know, I was thinking, what if I, uh, unpack here?
我在想，如果我在這裡打開東西呢？
Then all your stuff would be here
你的東西都會在這裡
Well?
怎麼樣？
What if all my stuff was here?
如果我的東西都在這裡的話？
Then you'd be going back and forth all the time, I mean
你會一直來來往往的
It doesn't make any sense
沒什麼道理
Okay
是
What if we live together and you understand what I'm saying?
如果我們住在一起 你瞭解我在說什麼？
You wanted it to be a surprise
你希望這是一個驚喜
Oh my God
我的天！
Chandler
錢德…
In all my life
我這一生…
I never thought I would be so lucky
從沒想過我會這麼幸運…
As to fall in love with my best
能愛上我最好的…
My best
好
There's a reason why girls don't do this
我最好的… 女生不這麼做是有原因的！
Okay, okay, okay, I'll do it
好，好，我來
I thought
我想…
Wait, I can do this
我做得到
I thought
我想…
That it mattered
如果我的東西都在這裡的話？
What I said
什麼？什麼？
Or where I said it
我說什麼和在哪裡說很重要
Then I realized
一個3，一個5…
The only thing that matters is that you
但我發現唯一重要的是你…
You make me happier
你使我比我能想像的更快樂
Than I ever thought I could be
And if you let me
如果你願意…
I will spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way
我要用這一生 來讓你有同樣感覺
Monica
摩妮卡？
Will you marry me?
嫁給我好嗎？
Yes
好
Can we come in yet? We're dying out here
我們可以進來了嗎？ 我們要急死了！
Come in, come in
進來！進來！
I'm engaged
-我們訂婚了！ -好！
Hey
喬伊！
Hi
炸雞？
Hey, what have you guys been up to?
-嗨 -你們在幹嘛？
Oh, we were helping Chandler write his vows
幫錢德寫他的婚誓 但被他踢出來了…
But he kicked us out because Joey kept making inappropriate suggestions
因為喬伊一直做不恰當的建議
How is Monica, I love your sweet ass, inappropriate?
「摩妮卡，我愛你的美臀」 有什麼不恰當？
How's Monica coming along with her vows?
摩妮卡寫得怎麼樣？
Let's just say it's lucky she's got a sweet ass
這樣說吧，幸好她有一個美臀 因為她不太會寫
Because she's not so good at the writing
I can't believe this
真不能相信...
I can't believe in four weeks they're gonna be married
真不能相信再四個星期 他們就要結婚了！
Well, let's just hope it works
希望他們的婚姻成功
You know, nine out of ten marriages end in divorce
10個裡面有9個以離婚收場
Phoebe, that's not true
菲比，沒有的事
Yeah, you're right
你要走了？
How's the missus?
是啊，你說的對，你太太們好嗎？
I can't believe they've been together for three years
不能相信這兩個人！
Has it been that long?
-我喜歡 -好
Maybe it seems like less because they hid it from us for so long
感覺沒那麼久 因為他們瞞了我們很久
Hey, it's me
來了
I'm coming in
是我，進來了
I've had a very long, hard day
我今天辛苦了一整天
I'm gonna go get some chicken, you want some?
-我要去買炸雞，你要不要？ -不，謝了，不要炸雞，再見
No thanks, no chicken, bye-bye then
Are you okay?
你開玩笑？
I'm so sorry, he wouldn't leave
-你不能 -拜託！
He kept asking me if I wanted chicken
你還好吧？抱歉，他不肯離開 一直問要不要炸雞
Chicken?
炸雞？
I could eat some chicken
我可以來點炸雞
Hey, Jew
喬伊！
Yeah, can I get a three-piece, some coleslaw and some beans and a Coke?
我想要三塊雞，沙拉 豆子，還有可樂
Diet Coke
健怡可樂
I don't know why they didn't just tell us
他們知道你知道 但他們不知道瑞秋知道？
I know, I mean, it's not like we weren't cool about it
-我不知道他們為什麼不告訴我們 -好像我們不會認同似的
You? And you?
你？和你？
Yes, but you cannot tell anyone, no one knows
你不能說，沒有人知道
How? When?
怎麼？何時？
It happened in London
-在倫敦發生的 -在倫敦？！
In London?
-你愛我！ -不，我不！
The reason we didn't tell anyone was because we didn't want to make a big deal out of it
我們沒告訴任何人 不希望把它變成大事
But it is a big deal!
可是這是大事！
I have to tell someone
-我一定要告訴人 -不，不要！
You can't
-你不能 -拜託！
Please, please, we just don't want to deal with telling everyone, okay?
我們不想面對告訴大家之後的事 答應我你不會說
Please, just promise you won't tell
我本來要告訴你們的 可是她們要我答應不說
Alright
好！
I can't wait to be with you
等不及要和你在一起了，我告訴瑞秋我要洗幾個小時的衣服
I'll just tell Rachel I'm gonna be doing laundry for a couple hours
Laundry, huh? Is that my new nickname?
洗衣服？是我的新暱稱嗎？
Aww
怎麼？何時？
You know what your nickname is, Mr. Big
你知道你的暱稱是什麼，大…
Oh look, there's Monica and Chandler, hey!
看，是摩妮卡和錢德 嘿！嘿，你們兩個！嘿！
Hey, you guys! Hey!
你們還沒玩完嗎？
Chandler and Monica! Chandler and Monica!
-錢德和摩妮卡！ -我的天！
Oh my God! Chandler and Monica!
錢德和摩妮卡！ 錢德和摩妮卡！
Oh my God!
我的天！
Oh my eyes! My eyes!
-我的眼睛！我的眼睛！ -菲比！菲比！
Phoebe, Phoebe!
菲比和喬伊
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay!
-沒事的！沒事的！ -不！他們在親熱！
No, they're doing it!
I know, I know!
我知道！我知道！
You know!
-你知道？ -對，我知道！
Yes, I know, and Joey knows, but Ross doesn't know, so you have to stop screaming!
喬伊知道，但羅斯不知道 你得停止尖叫！
Hey, what's going on?
-怎麼樣啊？ -嗨！
What?
什麼？
Nothing! Oh God, we're just so excited that you might get this apartment!
老天！我們好興奮 你可能會搬來這兒！
Actually, it looks really good!
-事實上，看起來不錯 -看來很不錯！
Yeah, it looks pretty good!
Get in here!
過來這裡！來！
Okay, so now they know you know, and they don't know that Rachel knows?
他們知道你知道 但他們不知道瑞秋知道？
Yes
好
You know what, it doesn't matter who knows what, now enough of us know that we can just tell them we know!
現在有足夠的人知道了 就可以告訴他們我們知道
Now all the lying and the secrets will finally be over!
謊言，秘密終於可以結束了
Or, we could not tell them we know, and have a little son of our own!
或者我們不要告訴他們我們知道 我們可以找點小樂子
Alright honey, we better go, we're gonna catch that movie
好，該走了，如果想趕上電影的話
Bye!
好
Bye Chandler!
錢德…
I miss you already
再見，錢德，我已經開始想你了
Okay, did you see that, with the inappropriate and the pinching?
你看到了嗎？ 她很不恰當地捏我一下？
Actually, I did!
我看到了
Okay, so now do you believe that she's attracted to me?
你現在相信她喜歡上我了吧？
Oh my God!
我的天！
Oh my God, she knows about us!
我的天！ 我的天，她知道我們的事！
Phoebe knows about us!
-菲比知道我們的事！ -我沒有告訴她們
Well, I didn't tell them!
Them?
她們？誰是她們？
Who's them?
Uh, Phoebe and Joey!
菲比和喬伊
Joey?
喬伊！
And Rachel!
還有瑞秋
I would have told you, but they made me promise not to tell!
我本來要告訴你們的 可是她們要我答應不說
Oh man, they think they are so slick messing with us!
她們以為他們很厲害，玩我們！
But see, they don't know that we know that they know!
可是，他們不知道 我們知道他們知道
So...
不
Ah yes, the messers become the messies!
玩人的變成被玩的！
Oh my God, he wants me to come over and feel his bicep and more!
我的天，他要我過去 摸他的二頭肌還有別的！
Are you kidding?
你開玩笑？
No!
不
I cannot believe he would do that to my...
我不相信他會對摩妮卡這樣…
Wha...
什麼？
Joey, do they know that we know?
喬伊？他們知道我們知道了嗎？
No
不
Joey!
喬伊！
They know you know
-他們知道你們知道 -我就知道！
Oh, I knew it!
什麼？我不懂
Oh, I cannot believe those two!
不能相信這兩個人！
They thought that they could mess with us, they're trying to mess with us!
他們以為可以玩我們？ 他們想要玩我們？
They don't know that we know they know we know!
他們不知道我們知道 他們知道我們知道
And Joey, you can't say anything!
喬伊，你什麼也不能說
Couldn't if I wanted to!
即使我想說也不知道要怎麼說
Listen, this is totally getting out of hand, okay?
-這太爆笑了！ -錢德！
She wants me to put lotion on her!
這完全失控了！ 她要我替她抹乳液！
She's bluffing!
她說大話！
No, look, she's not backing down, she went like this!
她沒有退縮，她像這樣：
He's not backing down, he went to get lotion!
他沒有退縮，他去拿乳液了
Oh man, aren't you guys done yet?
你們還沒玩完嗎？
Joey, look, just look at it this way, the sooner Phoebe breaks Chandler, the sooner this is all over and out in the open...
菲比早點攻破錢德 這事就早一點完全公開
Ooh, I like that
-我喜歡 -好
Okay
是
Oh, okay, show him your bra
-好，好，好，好，你贏了！ -哈！
He's afraid of bras, can't work them
好，給他看你的內衣 他最怕內衣，他不會解內衣
Wow, you didn't rip off any buttons
哇！你沒拉掉任何扣子
Not my first time
這不是第一次
You go back out there and you seduce her until she cracks!
回去那兒 勾引她直到解決她
Okay, give me a second
好，給我一秒鐘
Did you clean up in here?
-你清理了這兒？ -當然
Of course
Oh, you're going?
你要走了？
Um, not without you, lover
除非你一起來，愛人
So, this is my bra
這是我的內衣
It's very, very nice
非常非常的好看
Well, come here
過來
I'm very happy we're going to have all the sex
我非常開心我們要上床了
You should be, I'm very bendy
你應該開心的，我的柔軟度很好
I'm going to kiss you now
-我現在要吻你了 -如果我沒先吻你的話
Not if I kiss you first
Well, I guess there's nothing left for us to do but kiss
我想我們除了接吻 沒有別的事可做了
Here it comes
來了
Our first kiss
我們的初吻
Okay, okay, okay, you win
-好，好，好，好，你贏了！ -哈！
I can't have sex with you
-我不能和你上床 -為什麼不？
And why not?
Because I'm in love with Monica
-因為我愛摩妮卡 -你什麼？
You're really in love with Monica
能愛上我最好的…
What?
什麼？
Lover, that's right, I love her
愛她！對，我愛她！ 我愛她！
I love her
我也愛你，錢德
I love you, Monica
我愛你，摩妮卡
I love you too, Chandler
我也愛你，錢德
I thought you guys were doing it, I didn't know you were in love
我以為你們兩個只是上床 我不知道你們戀愛了
So that's it, it's over, everybody knows
就是這樣，結束了 大家都知道了
Well, actually, Ross doesn't
我看到了
Yes, and we'd appreciate it if no one told him yet
-其實，羅斯還不知道 -請大家先不要告訴他
No
不
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Get off my sister!
放開我妹妹！
You know, your friend's getting married, it's got to change things
朋友要結婚了 很多事會改變的
You really think it'll be that different?
你想會不一樣嗎？
How could it not be?
你怎麼寫出來的？
I mean, pretty soon they're going to be having kids
怎麼能不變呢？ 他們很快會有小孩…
And then they're just going to be hanging out with other couples who have kids
會和其他有孩子的夫婦在一起
And then maybe they're going to have to leave the city
也許他們會搬離城市…
To be near a Volvo dealership
到某個靠近富豪車商的地方
Well, things change
事情會變的
I don't want them to move to a Volvo dealership
我不要他們搬到 賣富豪車的地方
It'll be okay, Joe
喬伊，會沒事的
Sorry, I just, I like things the way they are
抱歉，我只是… 我希望能像以前一樣
Hey, who's this little naked guy?
這個光著身子的小孩是誰？
Uh, that little naked guy would be me
這個光著身子的小孩是我
Oh, look at the little thing
你看看這小東西
Yes
好
Yes, fine, that is my penis
是，好，那是我的小雞雞 我們現在可以做大人了嗎？
Can we be grown-ups now?
Who are those people?
-這些是誰？ -問倒我了
Not me
-不 -喬伊！
Oh, that's Nana right there, in the middle
那中間的是奶奶
Wow
不
Let's see
-哇 -我看看
Me and the gang at Java Joe's
「我和在爪哇喬店裡的那一群」
Wow, Monica, you look just like your grandmother
摩妮卡，你很像你祖母 那時她幾歲？
How old was she there?
如果我的東西都在這裡的話？
我看看，1939
Yeah, uh, 24, 25
對，24，25
Huh, looks like a fun gang
看來很快樂的一群
Ooh, look, look, look, look, look
看，看，看！ 我找到摩妮卡光著身子的
I got Monica naked
No, no, that would be me again
不，這還是我
Hey, you guys
-嘿，大夥兒 -怎麼樣啊？
Hey
喬伊！
What's going on?
-怎麼樣啊？ -嗨！
Well, we were just talking about you guys getting married and how great it is
你們要結婚了，非常的好
Yeah, you can get a Volvo
對，你們會買一台富豪 如果你們真的要那樣
If that's what you really want
Oh, that's so sweet
你們真好
So, we both finished our vows
-我們都寫完了婚誓 -可以看嗎？
Oh
不
Can we read them?
我們可以進來了嗎？ 我們要急死了！
Yeah, just as long as I don't hear Taylor's and he doesn't hear mine, okay?
只要我不看到錢德的 他不看到我的就好
Okay
是
Oh
不
Oh, that's beautiful
好美
Oh, funny one, that's a good one
好好笑！很好！
Monica, will you marry me?
嫁給我好嗎？
What? I don't get it
什麼？我不懂
Oh, yeah
是呦！
Oh, man, this is hilarious
-這太爆笑了！ -錢德！
Chandler
錢德…
Chandler?
Don't worry, honey, we'll make yours funnier
甜心，別擔心 我們會讓你的好笑一點
Dude, I have never known love like this
-老兄… -我從沒見過這樣的愛
You really like it?
-你真的喜歡？ -老兄！
Dude
錢德…
How did you write this?
你怎麼寫出來的？
I stole Monica's and changed the name
我偷了摩妮卡的 改成我的名字
You can't do that
我不確定我能這麼說
If he goes first, he can
-你不能這麼做！ -如果他先講的話就可以！
You
你？和你？